

# Amine DAOUDI +213662777412 +213661990266 aminesihe@hotmail.com Skype ID: aminesea

# **Head of Human Resources**

# PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY AND OBJECTIVE

A Head of Human Resources with over 15 years of progressive executive-level experience augmented by a strong background in Human Resources & business administration; a proven ability to function as a Strategic HR Manager by developing and implement successful Human Resources development strategies to support business employees, processes, immigration and Administration operations. I have thereby built transformational leadership skills, and developed a strong business background through effective interpersonal and strategic planning skills. My passion lies in acquiring new knowledge and implementing continuous quality improvement strategies, which simplify and optimize the workplace. I focus on adding value and measurable impact to the human resource role and department, and within all levels of the organizational structure.

### **HIGHLIGHTS AND QUALIFICATIONS**

- Multilingual: Fluent in written and spoken English, Arabic, French, and Spanish
- SAP/Oracle software experience
- Immigration specialist as per the labor law for different countries excise activities sin Country from Europe, Asia and Africa
- Excellent computer skills: MS Office, Internet and HTML.
- Deep Knowledgeable in U.S., Canadian, GCC & Algerian (Maghreb Region) labor Law.
- Effective communication, coaching, leadership and interpersonal skills with the ability to work effectively with employees at all levels of the organization.
- Experience in the HR generalist role
- Experience in Recruitment, Talent, Performance, and Change Management strategies
- Able to work autonomously to meet impending deadlines, and be responsible for effective time management strategies within fast-paced work environments

**Work Experience** 

# Country HR Manager LTHE Larsen Toubro Hydrocarbon Engineering Limited April 2019 to present (SWGF/EPC Project)

- Plan and coordinate an organization's workforce to best use employees' talent
- Government affairs relationship
- Edit procedure of relocation of Indians to host country as per law of the country
- Follow rules of immigration from India to Host country by preparing their admin and immigration files as per labor law.
- edit different correspondence to different authorities regarding foreign manpower in host country, their Residence permit, taxes to be paid, declaration in Social services and Medical insurances, IRG and fiscal contribution according to host country law.
- Link an organization's management with Its employees
- Administer employee services
- Advise managers on organizational policies, such as equal employment opportunity and sexual harassment
- Manage the activities of direct reports to ensure that all works is carried out in an efficient manner in line with business plan, policies and procedures.
- Manager the performance management process annual objective and developing staff though coaching constructive feedback
- Identify employee's training and development needs and in conjunction with human capital
- Create and execute learning strategies and programs
- Evaluate individual and organizational development needs
- Implement various learning methods companywide (e.g. coaching, job-shadowing, online training)
- Design and deliver e-learning courses, workshops and other trainings
- Assess the success of development plans and help employees make the most of learning opportunities
- Place of the state of the sta
- Lead meeting with Different Ministries to get approval of different files.
- Oversee an organization's recruitment, interview, selection, and hiring processes
- Handle staffing issues, such as mediating disputes and directing disciplinary procedures

- Supervise the temporary work permit process and to make expiates staff working in legal way in the country.
- Being part of the management incident team to find solution to every sudden incident and move one with updating procedures and take immediate actions
- Compensation and benefits task for our people under direct contract
- Negotiation technical assistant companies to provide employees for EPC project.
- Approve different invoices for our contractors.
- Make strategy on short and long term With editing and proposal new vision to keep the company and business always being managed by good and talented employees
- Creation of Motivation system and process to keep employees active and targeting the company objectives.

Senior International Human Resources Manager Consultant Pure Momentum Consulting California Region April 2017 to present Roles and Responsibilities

- Provide consultation and guidance to senior management and organizational partners in the interpretation of human resource management policies and procedures for client companies.
- Ensure HR programs and services are in compliance with established policies, procedures, and state/federal/international laws and regulations
- Support the application of research-based best practice strategies to support organizational compliance and risk management strategies.
- Leading the training programs and provide exact training required for team and other companies steam to develop competencies
- Provide advice on employee recruitment, on boarding, training, disciplinary, and termination processes, and advice on appropriate outcomes.
- Support client companies to strategically integrate effective HR processes, programs and practices into their daily operations.
- Providing support in restruction of or new changes on company organization chart to minimize costs. design and develop comprehensive programs for training, including corporate topics, HR training, and compliance training
- Select the ideal training methods or activities for a particular purpose and audience (online, role playing, mentoring, on the job training, professional development classes, etc.)
- Market and promote training opportunities to employees in an compelling way

Human Resources Manager for GEAT.
GE Algeria Turbines
Joint Venture between General Electric & Sonelgaz
February 2016 to March 2017
Manufacturing.

**Roles and Responsibilities** 

- Lead the project of Integration of Alstom legacy employees to General Employees with success.
- Responsible for all HR functions within company, including recruitment, employee training, compensation and benefits, and HR policy development.
- Managed a staff of over 200 employees in both business Grid and Thermal Services, in Algeria, Tunisia, and Morocco
- Responsible for all HR functions within company GEAT Spa, including recruitment, compensation and benefits, and HR policy development.
- Served as an Advisor for all expatriate assignments and immigration process, and liaised with domestic and international immigration departments as needed.
- Served as an Investigator with the investigation team in MENAT (Middle East North Africa & Turkey) region, related to all compliance infraction cases.
- Established and implemented a 20 person cohort leadership and technical training program
  for new University graduates, to increase the company recruitment pool, as well as promote
  new employee engagement and retention.
- Designed and implemented a company-wide performance management and evaluation system that was linked to the core vision and objectives of the business. Provided on-going consultation to senior and departmental management on performance related issues, and organizational culture enhancement.
- Implemented an innovative strategy of recruitment for the new JV training plan for new recruiters and prepared the salary scale in accordance with Algerian labor law.
- Provided senior management and other departmental leadership with various types of employee- related analysis and reports including attrition, absence, compensation, annual leave, overtime costs and headcount.
- Designed and implemented a company-wide performance management and evaluation system that was linked to the core vision and objectives of the business. Provided on-going consultation to senior and departmental management on performance related issues.
- Design and develop comprehensive programs for training, including corporate topics, HR training, and compliance training
- Select the ideal training methods or activities for a particular purpose and audience (online, role playing, mentoring, on the job training, professional development classes, etc.)
- Market and promote training opportunities to employees in an compelling way that provides all necessary information
- Conduct regular, whole-organization needs assessments, identifying skills or knowledge gaps that need addressing
- Utilize training best practices and education principles
- Analyze and incorporate new training methods and techniques
- Develop and prepare educational/training aids and materials, as needed
- Evaluate effectiveness of training courses and provide summary reports to management, determining impact of training on employee skills and corporate goals
- Collaborate with and connect internal stakeholders and liaise with various experts regarding instruction and training planning

HR Manager for Algeria-Tunisia & Morocco (NWA) Alstom Power Thermal Service & Grid Solution August 2015 to January 2016 Energy and Power.

#### **Role & Responsibilities:**

- Lead the project of Integration of Alstom legacy employees to General employees with success.
- Responsible for all HR functions within company, including recruitment, employee training, compensation and benefits, and HR policy development.
- Managed a staff of over 200 employees in both business Grid and Thermal Services, in Algeria, Tunisia, and Morocco.
- Drove organizational cultural compass changes for employees, and championed the transition from Alstom Culture to GE Culture, by designing both cognitive and operational models for employees, to effectively facilitate successful adaptations of new ideologies and methodologies in Algeria, Tunisia and Morocco.
- Exhibited and implemented in-depth knowledge regarding labor laws and HR best practices in the Maghreb Region: Algeria, Tunisia, and Morocco.
- Calculation of yearly Bonus and update the ALPS system according to the performance of employees.
- Managed development planning and succession planning of all employees using ORACLE/SAP system data base.
- Negotiated departure and outplacement of employees due to downsizing and restructuring of the Power organization.
- Investigate for non compliance case (5 cases).

HR Manager-Renewable Working Contract on behalf of Joint Venture of Oil and Gas June 2007 to March 2014

#### **Role and Responsibilities**

- Managed multicultural staffing, approximately 700 personnel, including locals and expatriates. This included having overall responsibility for Implementation and preparation the annual interviews of selected candidates, in collaboration with the Managers of different departments, according to their needs.
- Extrapolated departmental and individualized human capital plans from the approved business plan, to promote for efficient and effective talent sourcing and acquisition.
- Played an active role in HR projects such as job training and evaluation, grade and reward policy review, sales bonus system, organizational restructuring and executed relevant actions
- Coordinated between local authorities and the Joint Venture to finalize approved requests of recruiting expatriates, according the Algerian labor law.
- Provided employees with quarterly performance feedback and kept them motivated through coaching, performance development strategies, and incentive allocations.
- Performed disciplinary staff management duties, including resourcing understaffed departments, refereeing disputes, administering company, disciplinary procedures, and terminating employees.

HR Coordinator.
Structural Steel, Tanks Erections and Maintenance Company TARSI
In Amenas Project/Client JGC/KBR
Association on behalf of BP/SH/Statoil
December 2005 to May 2006

#### **Role & Responsibilities**

- Facilitated negotiations between workers and company administration in regards to payroll processes and concerns.
- Provided translation support during various meetings with executive leaders, stakeholders, and employees of KBR.
- Edited all correspondences between the client JK and Tarsi Company, in order to improve communications between both administrations, under the prevue of the site manager.
- Managed the demobilization of personnel, and prepared listing of different disciplines that needed to be demobilized, in adherence to company policy.
- Ensured the delivering of merchandise for the clients, in accordance to predetermined deadlines.

Storage Manager
TONIC Emballage (Company of transforming paper)
Bouismail, Algeria
January 2003 to January 2004

#### **Role & Responsibilities**

- Served as a translator for employees, clients, vendors, and company management
- Worked as a manager of storage, delivering more than 200 tons of paper each day and controlling the quality of paper production with the collaboration of the production manager.
- Managed group of 20 employees, and oversaw the manufacturing of merchandise to be fabricated according to client's demands.
- Nominated and evaluated employees for distribution of the monthly PRI (Monthly Bonus), according to efforts, evaluation and quantity supplied.

## **EDUCATION AND RELEVANT CERTIFICATIONS**

- Bachelors of Arts in Arts and Languages, June 2002, University of Algiers. (Fluent in English, Arabic, French, and Spanish).
- Graduate Studies in International Management, January 2012- 2013, Liverpool University
- Certificate for DPSI from Metropolitan University of London, UK (Consecutive Interpreting), December 2008.
- Certificate for Technical Procedures Writing and Technical Translation, University of Rennes France, 2009
- Compliance and Investigation Training Certification with (General Electric, MENAT Region).

